Shamira Jones Full Stack Developer

803-995-5768 | sjones.arise@gmail.com https://github.com/mira87/ https://www.linkedin.com/in/shamira-jones/ https://www.behance.net/shamirajones1/

PROFILE

Full Stack Developer who loves to build code that remains semantic, functional, scalable, and responsive. Constantly holding myself to a high standard, I find it invigorating to develop code that uses best practices and sets new standards in User Experience. With a background in Graphic Design, I am familiar with the creative process and always aim to build exceptional code that remains visually appealing.

SKILLS

LANGUAGES: JavaScript, Ruby, SQL, HTML, CSS, Python **SERVER-SIDE:** Node.js, Express Framework, Django

CLIENT-SIDE: React JS, Bootstrap, jQuery, AJAX, Responsive Design

DATABASES: MongoDB, Mongoose,

OTHER: Git, Github, Heroku, UXPin, Balsamiq, Adobe Lightroom, Adobe Indesign, Adobe Illustrator, Adobe

Photoshop, Creative Process

DEVELOPMENT EXPERIENCE

Adulting Task: http://adultingtasks.herokuapp.com

App for allowing those who are becoming adults to learn tasks that every adult should learn how to complete..

Japan's Memory Due I: https://mira87.github.io/memory-game/
Designed and developed an interactive game using HTML, JavaScript, and CSS to scale content and elements for mobile deployment.

Cheer Ups: https://github.com/mira87/Cheer-Ups
Created a full-stack application that encourages users. Frameworks used include MongoDB, Heroku, Mongoose, Express, JavaScript, HTML, and CSS.

Trailer Tracker: https://dctalk1234.github.io/trailer-tracker-frontend/

App that allows users to search Movie trailers in our database and OMBD's database for the purpose of finding trailers for movies they may want to add to a playlist or category. Utilize frameworks including React, CSS, Express, MongoDB, Heroku, and Mongoose, and BootStrap.

EDUCATION

Full Sail University, Bachelors of Graphic Design

02/2019 - 07/2021

General Assembly, Software Engineering Immersive Remote

08/2019 - 11/2019

500 full-time hours in a full-stack program conducted in a remote setting, providing experience with the latest front- and back-end programming languages, tools, and methodologies including: HTML, CSS, SASS, Javascript, jQuery, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Ruby, Ruby on Rails, AngularJS, NodeJS, ReactJS, Wordpress, Git, Github, and Agile/Scrum.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Customer Service Contractor, Arise

01/2019 - Present

- Yielded increased Customer Satisfaction, Sales and reduced Average Handling Times by maintaining great oral communications with customers.
- Troubleshot /debugged equipment and software such as Avaya, CSG, and Citrix applications in order to maintain a working environment.

Photographer, Lifetouch

05/2018 - 11/2018

- Maintained effective oral communications with teachers and school officials in order to maintain a functional and safe environment for over 500 students.
- Lead a team of 10 photographers through motivation, delegation of tasks, coordination of daily plans and remaining a strong team player.